现在让我们看看世界人口的年龄特征。你在这里看到的是一个数字
Let's look now at the age profile of the world population. What you can see here are a number
曲线，称为人口金字塔。我在这里有六个他们六个
of curves, which are referred to as population pyramids. I've got six of them here for six
不同的国家，你可以看到他们有不同的形状。在左边
different countries and you can see that they have quite different shapes. On the left hand
每个金字塔的一侧，我们都有男性年龄的分布。在右手侧，
side of each pyramid, we have a distribution of the age of males. On the right hand side,
我们有女性的年龄分布。
we have the age distribution of females.
让我们来看看澳大利亚的人口金字塔。我们可以看到的可能是超过这个时代
Let's look at the population pyramid for Australia. What we can see is that perhaps past the age
六十，男性和女性的人口开始逐渐减少，基本上，
of sixty, the population of both males and females starts to taper off and that's essentially,
人们死于老年的影响。你可以看到大约三十到三十岁
the effect of people dying of old age. You can see that around the age of thirty to thirty
五，人口中有一点冲击，这将反映出人口的飙升
five, there is a bit of a bump in the population and that would reflect either a spike in the
三十到三十五年前的出生率或者也许是移民涌入该国。
birth rate thirty to thirty five years ago or perhaps, a surge in immigration into the country.
如果我们看一下日本的人口金字塔，我们会发现它有一个非常非常不同的东西
If we look at the population pyramid for Japan, we see that it has a very, very different
形状确实。我们可以看到这里逐渐减少，这表明诞生了
shape indeed. We can see a taper down here and what that indicates is that the birth
该国的税率正在下降。我们还可以看到日本人的生活很长。
rate in the country is falling off. We can also see that the Japanese are very long lived.
八十岁以上的人比澳大利亚人多得多。我们也可以看到
There are many more people aged above eighty than there are in Australia. We can also see
有效的四十五岁以上人口很多。这意味着
that there is this large area of people aged above effectively forty-five. This means that
他们社会中有相当大比例的老年人并没有太多
they have quite a large proportion of elderly people in their society with not too many
年轻人进来取代他们。
young people coming in to replace them.
德国的曲线，你可以看到它也是完全不同的。它有这个巨大的膨胀
The curve for Germany, you can see it's also quite different. It's got this big bulge in
五十到六十的范围表明几乎开始的人口繁荣
the range fifty to sixty which indicates something about a population boom that started nearly
六十年前。
sixty years ago.
中国的人口金字塔有许多非常有趣的肿块和颠簸，
The population pyramid for China has got a number of quite interesting lumps and bumps,
这可能反映了该国历史上的许多事件。
which probably reflect many events in the history of that country.
印度的人口金字塔也具有非常独特的形状，并且有效地代表着
The population pyramid for India also has a very unique shape and effectively, represents
事实上，印度的预期寿命远低于其他国家的预期寿命
the fact that the life expectancy in India is much less than it is in countries such
如澳大利亚，德国，美国或日本。
as Australia, Germany, United States or Japan.
现在，我要做的是突出一个年龄段，年龄在二十岁到二十岁之间
Now, what I'm going to do is to highlight a band of ages, the ages between twenty and
六十。这些是在这些社会中工作的老年人。所以，不到二十的人
sixty. These are working aged people in these societies. So, people less than twenty are
一般得到父母的支持。他们通常在学校或大学。
generally being supported by their parents. They're typically at school or at university.
60岁以上的人已退休，并得到国家或子女的支持。
Those above sixty have retired and are being supported either by the state or by their children.
因此，理解群体的一个非常重要的概念就是所谓的依赖
So, a really important concept in understanding populations is what’s called the dependency
比;这是受抚养人数量，即儿童和老年人的比例
ratio; that's the ratio of the number of dependents, that's children and older people to the number
工人，赚取工资，工作和支持年轻人和老年人的人。
of workers, the people who are earning a salary, doing a job and supporting the young and the old people.
对于抚养比，低值是好的。此处绘制的依赖率
For dependency ratio, a low value is good. The dependency ratios that are plotted here
对于澳大利亚而言，我们可以看到他们在2010年取得了最低成绩
are for Australia and we can see that they achieved a minimum in the year 2010, that's
当抚养比率达到最佳时，它可能是最好的。随着我们及时前进，
when the dependency ratio was the best it could possibly be. As we move forward in time,
抚养比增长。事实上，它变得更糟，这意味着有更多的老人
the dependency ratio grows. In fact, it gets worse, that means that there are more elderly
少数劳动老年人支持人和年轻人。所以，
people and young people to be supported by a smaller number of working aged people. So,
我们能够以同样的方式保持社会运作的唯一方式是我们需要每个人
the only way we can keep our society working the same way as it has is we need each individual
人变得更有生产力，或者我们可以为社会增加机器人工人，增加
person to become more productive or we could add robotic workers to the society, to increase
在不需要更多人的情况下完成的工作量。
the amount of work that's going to be done without requiring more human beings.
最重要的是，如果我们希望拥有相同的护理标准
The bottom line is that in the future, if we want to have the same standard of care
对于年轻人和老年人而言，它将由少数人提供
for young people and elderly people and it's going to be provided by a smaller number of
老年人工作，那些工作老年人需要更高效。每一个
working aged people, then those working aged people need to be more productive. Each one
那些人需要做的工作比人们今天要做的更多。
of those people needs to do more work than people have to do today.
所以，这就是我们必须期待的。每个工作年龄的人都要做更多
So, that's what we have to look forward to. Each working aged person having to do more
工作比几年前的人做的多。替代方案是我们引入
work than people did a few years ago. The alternative for that is we introduce into
混合，机器人技术意味着我们引入机器人工人。所以，他们要么
the mix, robotic technology that means we introduce robotic workers. So, they either
自己做一些工作，或者帮助人类工人提高工作效率。
do some of the work themselves or they help the human workers to become more productive.
让我们看一下医疗保健与年龄的关系，我们可以清楚地看到这一点
Let's look here at health care versus age and what we can see quite clearly is that
对于非常年轻的人来说，他们需要一定程度的健康干预，然后才能
for very young people, they require certain amount of health intervention and then for
他们生命的早年，也许是五到四十岁，他们也不需要
the early years of their life, perhaps from five through forty, they don't require too
很多健康干预但超过四十岁，人们需要个人，
much health intervention but above the age of forty, people need on an individual basis,
更多的健康干预措施。这基本上意味着老年人需要更多的医疗保健。
more health interventions. It basically means elderly people require more health care.
因此，随着我们的人口老龄化，这样的图表会变得更加极端
So, as our population gets older, graphs like this are going to get much, much more extreme
这对我们这个提供医疗保健的社会提出了真正的挑战
and that presents a real challenge to us as a society to provide the health care that
需要提供。如果您去过医院，您会发现它们非常令人难以置信
needs to be provided. If you've ever visited a hospital, you know that they are incredibly
繁忙的地方。有各种各样的工作正在进行中。有工作从一个病房搬家
busy places. There’s all sorts of work going on. There is work moving people from one ward
到另一个。有外科医生在进行手术。有人洗衣服。
to another. There are surgeons performing operations. There are people doing laundry.
有人在做饭。医院里发生的各种活动都是雇用的
There are people doing cooking. All sorts of activities happening in a hospital employ
很多人，这使它变得昂贵。
a lot of people and that make it expensive.
或许，机器人技术可以在这里发挥作用。机器人已经做得很好了
So perhaps, robot technology has a role to play here. Robotics is already making quite
对手术领域产生重大影响。事实上，它在技术上更像是远程操作。
a significant impact in the area of surgery. In fact, it's more technically teleoperation.
我们在这里看到的是一些外科医生，远程操作或控制内部的小型机器人工具
What we can see here are some surgeons, teleoperating or controlling small robotic implements inside
病人的身体在这里。因此，这些是正在进行工作的机器人手臂
the body of a patient over here. So, these are the robot arms that are doing the work
在人体内部。这些人正在控制那些机器人手臂。
inside the human body. These people here are controlling those robotic arms.
做这种手术的好处是外科医生可以更高效
The advantage of doing this sort of surgery is that the surgeons can be more productive
因为我们在患者身上做了非常小的切口，所以他们恢复得更快
and because we make very small incisions in the patients, they recover much more quickly
不得不花更少的时间在医院，这对医疗保健系统是一个净收益。
having to spend less time in hospital and that's a net benefit to the health care system.
为医院提出的其他类型的机器人技术包括仪器
Other sorts of robotic technology that are being proposed for hospitals include instruments
将自己从一个病房自动移动到另一个病房，以及可以接人的机器人
that move themselves automatically from one ward to another and robots that can pick people
也许，将他们从轮椅上升到床上或从床上升到轮椅上。很多
up, perhaps lift them from a wheelchair into a bed or from a bed into a wheelchair. A lot
医院的手术涉及将人们从一个地方转移到另一个地方。人很重
of operations in hospital involve moving people from one place to another. People are heavy
并且需要相当强壮的人才能让患者四处移动。
and will require quite strong people just to move patients around.
像这里所示的Asimo这样的人形机器人可能能够为老年人提供帮助
Humanoid robots such as Asimo shown here, might be able to provide assistance to elderly
人们在自己的家中。如果我们能够让人们在家中保持健康和快乐
people in their own homes. If we can keep people healthy and happy in their homes for
在更长的时间内，我们减少了他们需要花费的时间
a longer period of time, then we reduce the amount of time that they need to spend in
老年人护理，这是对社会的净利益。也许，机器人助手在
elderly care and that is a net advantage to society. So perhaps, robotic helpers in the
家可以帮助人们长时间呆在家里。
home can assist people staying in their homes for longer.